Juan C. Medina

2204 Hall Ln, Jeffersonville, IN 47130

(502) 356-6819 Cell

Juan_k555@hotmail.com

Objective

Finance and Accounting Intern position to capitalize on my Financial, Accounting and analytical skills. Looking to improve and gain a good amount of knowledge and contribute to the company's progress.

Summary

I have 6+ years of experience in different fields including: Administrative, Banking, Customer Service and Sales.

Most recently I have been working as a Sales Representative for WindowDecor.com from October 2016 to present.

I hold a High School diploma, 2.5 years of International Business (FCECEP Cali, Colombia), and currently pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Business.

Experience

Sales Representative / Customer Service

October 2016 - to present

WindowDecor.com

- Outbound/Inbound phone calls
- Schedule appointments with potential clients
- Demonstrate product selection
- Assist customer in their purchase
- Elaborate quotes, contracts, purchase orders
- Commercial estimating
- Build and maintain relationships with professionals such as builders, realtors, designers.
- Use of Microsoft Office

Sales Consultant

August 2015 – October 2016

Jeff Wyler Toyota of Clarksville

- Assist customers on selecting vehicles based on their needs
- Demonstrate and sell the different vehicles available in the dealership
- Assist customers with credit applications and prequalification processes
- Help customers with the negotiation process, maximizing profitability for the company
- Prepare the paperwork required for the vehicle purchase

- Collect any bank stipulations required for credit approval
- Deliver sold vehicles and explain the different features in the car
- Receive inbound phone calls (Sales, previous customers, etc.)
- Handle internet leads with the assigned process from the company
- Make outbound phone calls to prospects and previous customers.

Since I started in this company I have been one of the top performers with a recognition of "Sales Person of the Month" for the month of June (Corporate level)

Customer Service and Ordering Specialist

July 2013 - August 2015

United Services Inc.

- Handle inbound and outbound phone calls from customers and vendors
- Price quote elaboration
- Processing of orders
- Installation of products (When the business required extra help)
- Measurement, design and pricing of custom made closets
- Scheduling installation for customers
- Use of Microsoft Office

Specialized Bank Teller

July 2011 - May 2013

Banco de Occidente SA (Bank of Occident, Colombia)

- Assisting customer with their transactions and requests of information
- Handling of cash, checks and debit/credit card transactions
- Use of different banking systems
- Inbound and outbound phone calls
- Processing of documentation and transactions
- Analyze reports from specialized banks and Brinks (Money transportation) to ensure all transactions and amounts were accurate.
- Report any shortage or excess of money
- Work with team members to ensure all processes and procedures were performed according to bank's policies.
- Use of Microsoft Office

Skills

I am a hard worker with a very strong work ethic. Analytical person, quick thinker and quick learner. Tech savvy and strong negotiator. I have basic knowledge of Finance and Accounting. I like to be always on time, and I'm also always responsible of performing at a very high level. I believe in being disciplined and doing everything with excellence. I'm also bilingual in Spanish.

Education

High School Diploma

Joaquin de Cayzedo y Cuero (Cali - Colombia)

International Business – 5th Semester

FCECEP (Cali – Colombia)

English as a Second Language - College Level

Jefferson Community and Technical College – Downtown Louisville

Associates of Science in Business – Freshman year.

Ivy Tech Community and Technical College

Transferring to Indiana University Southeast next semester.

References are available upon request